# **Paul Landers**

(303) 898 - 3972 paul@thelanders.family https://P3L6.dev/resume https://github.com/P3L6

Experienced Software Engineer developing for MacOS & iOS, as well as Full Stack Web. Expertise with debugging, problem solving, and solution design architecture. Punctual communicator, patient, and thrives on a fully remote team. Mentors and assists teammates in their professional growth. Always open to new technologies: mindful of which tool is best suited for a task.

#### Software Skills

- Swift, Objective-C, Python, Typescript
- C++, C, Java, LATEX, Markdown
- Shell, Git, make, CMake, Redmine, Jira, Jenkins, Gitlab, Heroku, CircleCI
- OpenGL, Cocoa, GNUstep, iOS, Docker, Thrift, GraphQL
- Matlab, Vapor, React, Deno

## Experience

## Senior Software Engineer

Sept 2019 - Dec 2022

Doma (aka States Title)

Durham, NC

Full stack web application development for a Title & Escrow platform

**Tech:** Typescript, React, Postgres, Python, Django, Thrift, Github, Heroku, Azure, Jira, Docker, Kubernetes, CircleCI, GraphQL

- Doma Close for Realtor (Sept 2021 Dec 2022)
  - Guide technical direction for initial backend of an order status portal
  - Shipped a successful beta release of the order status portal on time, in 1 quarter
  - Architected solutions to work cleanly with legacy systems
  - Worked to improve developer systems and tools, unblocking common issues for teammates
- Athena TPS (Sept 2019 Sept 2021)
  - Lead development on a document templating service
  - Guide teammates as the team lead for a small team that grew in scope and responsibilities
  - Steer direction and evaluate technology options for greenfield projects
  - Contribute on the cross-team application architecture group, to increase tech cohesion across the organization
  - Help newer employees become familiar with codebase and tech stack
  - Created a tool to help team track work completed for an asynchronous standup

# Senior Software Developer

Aug 2014 - Sept 2019

Eggplant (aka Testplant)

Boulder, CO

 $Developed\ desktop\ software\ for\ a\ suite\ of\ functional\ testing\ products$ 

**Tech:** Swift, Objective-c, Cocoa, GNUstep, iOS, Python, C++, OpenCV, Docker, Gitlab, Jenkins, Jira, Git, MacOS, Linux, Windows, MinGW

- Lead feature development, working independently when needed on major features
- Developed cross-platform applications using Objective-c (Cocoa) and GNUstep
- Maintained Jenkins build server and build environments for Mac, Windows, Linux
- Identified and fixed complex bugs and issues, including inside GNUstep
- Migrated linux build machines to Docker images, to increase build stability
- Migrated all svn repositories to git. Frequently the team's go-to person for help with git

- Helped identify ideas and ways to improve the applications, both user facing improvements and internal technical improvements
- Part of an agile development team using scrum practices
- Keep up to date with Apple technologies and trends

## Software Engineer

Jan 2012 - Aug 2014

QiG Group, Greatbatch Medical

Broomfield, CO

 $\label{lem:medical device software development, including user interface, rendering engine, algorithms, data acquisition$ 

**Tech:** C++, Objective-c, Java, Svn, Git, CMake, Gradle, SQLite, Redmine, OpenGL, Matlab, iOS, WinCE

- Architect, design and implement software for a Clinician Programmer Application
- Maintained a Clinician Programmer device emulation environment on iOS
- Design, implement, and optimize a custom 3D rendering pipeline using OpenGL ES 2.0, Textures, shaders, vertex buffers, etc.
- Co-authored 2 Patents (US9943691B2, US9767255B2), and 2 Patent Disclosures
- Mathematically solve and implement algorithms designed for a Clinician Programmer
- Implement laboratory data acquisition virtual instruments with LabView
- Setup and run equipment during pre-clinical animal research labs
- Maintained xServe, Git, Redmine, Hudson and other internal servers for development team
- Assist in drafting and disclosing intellectual property
- Scrum master for software development team in agile

### Software Development Intern

QiG Group, Greatbatch Medical

Summer: 2011 Broomfield, CO

Worked with other developers to create an OpenGL-based rendering engine

## Boy Scout Canoe Trip Guide

Northern Tier National High Adventure Base

Summer: 2009,2010 Elv. MN

Lead week-long canoe trips for groups of scouts

### Education

University of Colorado at Boulder

Applied Mathematics

Minor: Computer Science

Boulder, CO Graduated Dec 2011

GPA: 3.459

### Other Projects

#### Quiz Tracker

- Developed an iOS app for the App Store, to track your score for a game of Jeopardy
- Built entire interface with SwiftUI

#### nccpipeband.org

- Rewrote website backend using php; including user log in system, user profiles/band roster, user permissions, restricted file access, events calendar
- As webmaster, maintain user lists and site pages
- Re-implemented the website again, using Joomla

## Tic Tac Cubed

• Developed an iOS game for the App Store, based on a tic tac toe variant

# Leadership

### Eagle Scout

Boy Scouts of America

- Excellent communication and interpersonal skills
- Ability to perform independently in many situations

#### Pipe Major

Northern Colorado Caledonia Pipe Band and Wake and District Public Safety Pipes and Drums

- Lead regular rehearsals for groups of 10-30 musicians
- Set the music to be played in the band, and teach it to members to ensure a cohesive style
- Help others keep their bagpipes in proper working order
- Lead band in parades and competitions

# Thanksgiving meal director

First Presbyterian Church

- Organized volunteers and planned meal for 2 years
- Meal served around 350 homeless each year, with over 100 volunteers

### Misc.

- Bagpipe Player
- WWDC Attendee
- Keyboard Enthusiast